Finding Aid for Timothy W. Wholihan papers, 1867-1948
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Timothy W. Wholihan papers 1867-1948
Wholihan, Timothy W.
0.3 linear feet.
85452 Aa 2
Railroad fireman, 1882-1887, and engineer, 1887-1934, for the Michigan Central Railroad. Miscellaneous personal and collected material relating to his interest in railroads, the Brotherhood of Locomotive Engineers, and his work with the Michigan Central Railroad; include membership cards and certificates, clippings, time tables, ca. 1870-1905, tire report, 1893, wage agreement, 1887, and photographs.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was the gift of Dr. and Mrs. John W. Wholihan (donor no. 6445 ).
Periodic additions to the records are not expected.
The collection is open to research.
Timothy W. Wholihan was long-time employee of the Michigan Central Railroad. He worked as railroad fireman from 1882 to 1887, and then as an engineer from 1887 to 1934.
The Wholihan collection is a small collection of miscellaneous materials accumulated by Wholihan as fireman and engineer with the Michigan Central Railroad. There are three small series in the collection: Miscellaneous; Brotherhood of Locomotive Engineers; and Michigan Central Railroad.
Subjects:
Brotherhood of Locomotive Engineers (U.S.); Michigan Central Railroad Company.; Railroads--Michigan.
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Jackson (Mich.); Leonidas (Mich.)--Railroad stations.; Michigan Central Railroad Company; Railroad accidents.; Railroad stations--Michigan--Leonidas.; Railroads--Michigan.
Genre Terms:
Photographs.
- Miscellaneous
  - Miscellaneous papers, undated (Box 1)
  - Membership cards in various railroad organizations, 1885-1923 (Box 1)
  - Newspaper clipping, 1948 (Box 1)
  - Photographs (Box 1)
- Brotherhood of Locomotive Engineers, 1885-1944
  - Miscellaneous certificates, 1885-1944 (Box 1)
  - Newspaper clipping, 1942 (Box 1)
- Michigan Central Railroad, 1867-1919
  - Miscellaneous information, 1867-1919 (Box 1)
  - Newspaper clipping on 1893 train wreck (Box 1)
  - Timetables, ca. 1870-1905 (Box 1)
  - Tire report, 1893 (Box 1)
  - Wage agreement, 1887 (Box 1)